A Guide to the Director's Office Correspondence and Subject Files of the Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 1954-1986
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Director's Office Correspondence and Subject Files of the Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation, 1954-1986
The Library of Virginia
44897
29.6 cubic feet (31 boxes)
Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation on 15 April 2010.
Historical Information
The Jamestown Foundation was created by an act of the General Assembly passed on March 29, 1958, to administer, develop, and maintain Jamestown Festival Park. The Foundation was administered by a board of trustees consisting of twenty-four members, eight appointed by the Speaker of the House from its membership, four appointed by the President of the Senate from its membership, and twelve members appointed by the Governor from the citizens of the Commonwealth. Effective July 1, 1976, the Foundation was renamed the Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation and also was charged with acquiring, operating, and maintaining Yorktown Victory Center at the request of the Virginia Independence Bicentennial Commission.
In addition to administering Festival Park and Victory Center, the Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation is charged with developing and maintaining national and international awareness of the important role played by Virginia in the creation of the United States through programs, related research, and educational programs. The overriding educational purposes of the Foundation were first recognized when the General Assembly declared the agency to be an educational institution within the definitions of the Code of Virginia. That action also identified Jamestown Festival Park and Yorktown Victory Center as historical museums and commemorative shrines by law. The Foundation actively directs private sector efforts to increase tourism in the areas in which the foundation has its centers.
Scope and Content
Contains correspondence and subject files belonging to Parke Rouse, Jr., the first executive director of the Jamestown Festival Park, and later the Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation. In addition, Rouse served as director of the Virginia Independence Bicentennial Commission. Includes correspondence, news releases, clippings, programs, minutes, maps, reports, publications, bylaws, contracts, invitations, speeches, financial records, lists, photographs, questionnaires, blueprints, budgets, plans, memorandums, and other sundry items. These files document the planning and commemoration of Virginia's 350th Anniversary, Virginia's Independence Bicentennial, and the Yorktown Bicentennial. In addition, there is information on First Assembly Day, the George Washington Bicentennial Center (Alexandria, Va.), the Western Virginia Bicentennial Center (Charlottesville, Va.), the Bicentennial Council of the Thirteen Original States, and the Yorktown Victory Center.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1954-1976.
Series II: History Files, 1956-1986
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence and Subject Files, 1954-1984., Extent: 13 boxes. (Box 1-13)
  - Virginia Commemorative Goodwill Visit - Press Clippings, 1956. (Box 1)
  - Color Production 1957. (Box 1)
  - Advisory Committee, 1957. (Box 1)
  - Book II (Box 1)
  - Facilities at Glass House Point, 1956 (Box 1)
  - APVA, 1957. (Box 1)
  - Mermaid Tavern Air Conditioning, 1960-1961. (Box 1)
  - Attorney General - Opinions of, 1957. (Box 1)
  - Colonial National Historical Park, 1957. (Box 1)
  - Commemorative Visit, 1957. (Box 1)
  - Committee - Education, 1957. (Box 1)
  - Committee - Executive, 1957. (Box 1)
  - Committee - Religion, 1957. (Box 1)
  - British Government, 1957. (Box 1)
  - Committee - Archives & History, 1957. (Box 1)
  - Committee - Arts, 1957. (Box 1)
  - Souvenirs, Incorporated, 1955-1957. (Box 1)
  - 1607, Inc., 1958-1962. (Box 1)
  - Budget Expenditures, 1980-1982. (Box 1)
  - Report on Audit, 1965. (Box 1)
  - 1607, Inc., 1958. (Box 1)
  - Jamestown Foundation General Ledger, 1966. (Box 1)
  - Virginia 350th Anniversary Celebration Corporation Minutes, 1955-1957. (Box 1)
  - Jamestown Foundation General Journal, 1958-1974. (Box 1)
  - General Assembly Report, 1958. (Box 1)
  - Local Fund Ledger, 1956. (Box 1)
  - Report on Future Status of Festival Park, 1957. (Box 1)
  - Summary Record of Jamestown Festival Park, 1957-1958. (Box 1)
  - Jamestown Foundation Minutes & By-laws, 1958-1961. (Box 1)
  - Jamestown Foundation Certificate of Incorporation & By-laws, 1957. (Box 1)
  - E.G. Wilson Consultant's Contract, 1977. (Box 1)
  - Jamestown Foundation - By-laws, etc., 1962. (Box 1)
  - Virginia 350th Anniversary Celebration Corporation, 1958-1960. (Box 1)
  - Lease Agreements, 1956-1977. (Box 1)
  - Merchandise Agreements, 1957-1958. (Box 1)
  - Car Decals, n.d.. (Box 1)
  - Newsclippings
    - 1957 (Box 2)
    - 1956 (Box 2)
    - "Deliverance," 1971 (Box 2)
    - Explorations, n.d. (Box 2)
    - Ft. Monroe, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Benjamin Franklin, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Green Springs, 1955 (Box 2)
    - Hunt, Rev. Robert, n.d. (Box 2)
    - 1955 (Box 2)
    - Bicentennial, 1976 (Box 2)
    - 1958 (Box 2)
    - 1959 (Box 2)
    - 1966 (Box 2)
    - 1969 (Box 2)
    - 1970 (Box 2)
    - 1971 (Box 2)
    - 1972 (Box 2)
    - 1974 (Box 2)
    - 1975 (Box 2)
    - 1976 (Box 2)
    - 1978 (Box 2)
    - Living History, 1978 (Box 2)
    - James Monroe, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Negroes, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Virginia - General, 1958 (Box 2)
    - Pilgrims, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Pocahontas, 1967 (Box 2)
    - Tobacco, 1971 (Box 2)
    - William & Mary, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
    - Yorktown, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Preliminary & Confidential United Kingdom Participation in the 1957 Jamestown Festival (Box 2)
  - Jamestown, 1957. (Box 2)
  - Jamestown Festival, 1957. (Box 2)
  - Personnel, Military & New World (incl. Photographs), 1957. (Box 2)
  - 350th Anniversary Jamestown Festival Guidebook, 1957. (Box 2)
  - School Groups, 1957. (Box 2)
  - Fort Personnel - Military, 1957. (Box 2)
  - Park Operations, 1957. (Box 2)
  - Jamestown Exposition 1907 (incl. Postcards), 1957-1971. (Box 2)
  - 1907 Lists - Smithsonian Material (incl. Photographs), 1970. (Box 2)
  - Jamestown Exposition of 1907, 1966-1969. (Box 2)
  - Old World Pavilion, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Colonial Parkway Signs, n.d. (Box 2)
  - New World Pavilion, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Jamestown Festival Official Program, 1957. (Box 2)
  - Talks, 1956. (Box 2)
  - "The Founders," (Home Daily Bulletin Routine Sheet) n.d. (Box 2)
  - Memos, Incoming, 1957-1958. (Box 2)
  - Memos, Outgoing, 1957-1958. (Box 2)
  - Exhibits - New World (No. II), 1956-1957. (Box 3)
  - Exhibits - New World, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Exhibits - Miscellaneous, 1957. (Box 3)
  - Federal Commission, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Federal Brochure, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Festival Brochure, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Festival Posters, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Festival Stamps, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Films, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Fire Dept. - Park, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Glass Factory, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - General Assembly Report, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Governor, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Guide Service, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Historical Booklets, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Indians, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Indians, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Jamestown Festival Park, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Highway Beautification Committee, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Invitations, 1958. (Box 3)
  - James Fort, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Jamestown Island, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Jamestown Maritime Corp., 1958. (Box 3)
  - Jamestown Transit Company, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Landscaping & Planting - Festival Park, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Legal Advisor, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Weekly Literature Distribution, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Magazine Article & Advertising, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Meetings, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Mathews Fund, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Plaques, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Military Participation, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Personnel, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Naturalized Citizens, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Passes, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Plymouth Plantation, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - Polish-American Congress, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Polish Government, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Resolutions, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Rolfe-Pocahontas Wedding Program, 1955-1958. (Box 3)
  - Roseburg Statue, 1957-1958. (Box 3)
  - School Groups, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Services Offered, 1958. (Box 3)
  - Ships (Susan Constant, Godspeed, & Discovery), 1964. (Box 3)
  - Ships - "The Ships of Jamestown's Day," 1963. (Box 3)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 1954. (Box 4)
  - Murran, Lewis A., Jr., 1957-1962. (Box 4)
  - Passes - Welcome Wagon, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Virginia State Travel Committee, 1963-1964. (Box 4)
  - Organizations - Virginia Travel Council, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Special Events - Commemorative Reunion Visit, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Organizations - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous - Jamestown Festival Park Letterhead Paper, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Jamestown - Miscellaneous, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Grounds & Buildings - General, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Grounds & Buildings - Pottery, 1963. (Box 4)
  - Grounds & Buildings - Pottery, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Grounds & Buildings - Bid for Work, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Grounds & Buildings - Office Expansion, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Jamestown Foundation - Board of Directors Meeting, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Grounds & Buildings - James Fort, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Films, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Educational Material - Jamestown Festival Park Brochure, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Grounds & Buildings - Pavilion Exhibits, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Grounds & Buildings - Flags & Seals, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Concessions - Gift Shop, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Educational Material - Requests, 1964. (Box 4)
  - Inquiry - Emily Whaley, 1954-1955. (Box 4)
  - Jetty Project, 1960. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Historical Project, 1957. (Box 4)
  - Photos & Newsclips, 1959-1962. (Box 4)
  - Inquiries - John Rolfe Reward, 1961-1962. (Box 4)
  - Visiting Groups, 1958. (Box 5)
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1958. (Box 5)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce, 1958. (Box 5)
  - Virginia State Library, 1957-1958. (Box 5)
  - Virginia Tour to England & Brussels, 1958. (Box 5)
  - Virginia Travel Council, 1958. (Box 5)
  - Ships, 1957-1958. (Box 5)
  - Visits - Convention Group Visits, 1963-1964. (Box 5)
  - Signs - Festival Park, 1957-1958. (Box 5)
  - Speeches, 1957-1958. (Box 5)
  - Statistics, 1957-1958. (Box 5)
  - State Highway Department, 1957-1958. (Box 5)
  - Ticket Sales, 1958. (Box 5)
  - Whittet & Shepperson, 1958. (Box 5)
  - Visitation - Teachers' Questionnaires, 1964. (Box 5)
  - Visitation - Groups & General, 1964. (Box 5)
  - Visitation - Attendance Statistics, 1964. (Box 5)
  - Visitation - Special Individuals or Groups, 1964. (Box 5)
  - Special Events - Southern Regional Education Board, 1964. (Box 5)
  - Special Events - World's Fair, 1964. (Box 5)
  - Special Events - Luncheon for Williamsburg Hotel & Motel Managers, 1964. (Box 5)
  - Special Events - General Assembly Day, 1964. (Box 5)
  - Special Events - Jamestown Day, 1964. (Box 5)
  - Commemorative Cruise Reunion, 1964. (Box 5)
  - Special Events - General, 1964. (Box 5)
  - Pocahontas, 1964. (Box 5)
  - Organizations - Williamsburg Chamber of Commerce & Other Chambers, 1964. (Box 5)
  - Burelle's Press Clipping Service, 1958-1959. (Box 6)
  - Celebrations Elsewhere, 1958. (Box 6)
  - College of William & Mary, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Colonial National Historical Park, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Colonial Williamsburg, 1957-1958. (Box 6)
  - Complaints, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Concessions Flyer Material, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Contributions, 1957-1958. (Box 6)
  - Costumes, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Courtesy Letters, 1957-1958. (Box 6)
  - Corporation, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Awards, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Bermuda Collection, 1958-1959. (Box 6)
  - Brochure, 1958-1959. (Box 6)
  - Brochure, 1958-1959. (Box 6)
  - Budget, 1959-1960. (Box 6)
  - Commonwealth Magazine, 1958-1959. (Box 6)
  - Chicken BBQ & Open House, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Conventions, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Exhibits - Old & New World Pavilions, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Festival Park - Maintenance & Operation, 1958-1959. (Box 6)
  - Films, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Gift Shop, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Glass House, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Highway Department - General, 1958-1959. (Box 6)
  - Inquiries
    - 1959 July-August (Box 6)
    - 1959 June (Box 6)
    - 1959 May (Box 6)
    - 1959 April (Box 6)
    - 1959 March (Box 6)
    - 1959 February (Box 6)
    - 1959 January (Box 6)
  - Inquiries & Requests, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Interpretive Signs, 1958-1959. (Box 6)
  - Jamestown Food, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Jamestown Foundation, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Memorandum, 1959. (Box 6)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation, 1957-1959. (Box 6)
  - Pass Policy & Distribution, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Photo Contest, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Jamestown Festival Park and Maintenance & Upkeep, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Photographs, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Questions & Remarks, 1958-1959. (Box 6)
  - Pocahontas Descent, 1957. (Box 6)
  - School Groups, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Services Offered, 1958-1959. (Box 6)
  - Ships, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Seal Ideas, 1954-1956. (Box 6)
  - Awards, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Special Events, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Special Events - General, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Special Visits, 1958-1959. (Box 6)
  - State Days, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Tour Companies, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Ballou & Justice (Architects & Engineers, Richmond, Va.), 1957-1958. (Box 6)
  - Book Sales, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Virginia Travel Council, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Visiting Groups, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Williamsburg Business Index, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Williamsburg Chamber of Commerce, 1959. (Box 6)
  - Appropriations, 1957-1958. (Box 6)
  - APVA, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Attendance Summary, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Advisory Committee, 1957-1958. (Box 6)
  - Ditto Masters, n.d. (Box 6)
  - British Government, 1958. (Box 6)
  - Correspondence - Temporary Tobacco Display, 1961-1962. (Box 6)
  - Tobacco, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Tobacco Exhibit - Treatment, 1962. (Box 6)
  - Temporary Tobacco Display - NWP, 1962. (Box 6)
  - Tobacco Exhibit - Events of 1612, 1956. (Box 6)
  - Tobacco Exhibit - 19th & 20th Century Tobacco, n.d.. (Box 6)
  - Tobacco Exhibit - Pre-Columbian, 1962. (Box 6)
  - Tobacco Exhibit - Special Exhibits, 1960-1962. (Box 6)
  - Tobacco Exhibit - Dioramas for Tobacco Anniversary, 1961. (Box 6)
  - Microfilm Reel - Hampton Roads Engineering, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Gift Shop, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Pottery, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Article - Building of Jamestown, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Article - Ships (reprint), 1966 (Box 7)
  - Costumes & Uniforms, 1966 (Box 7)
  - research, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Publicity - Clippings, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Publicity, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Publicity & Promotion, 1958 (Box 7)
  - Reunion - 10th Anniversary of Trip to England, 1966 (Box 7)
  - Exhibits - Plaque for Pocahontas, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Special Visits, 1959 July-Dec. (Box 7)
  - Special Visits, 1959 Jan.-June (Box 7)
  - Tour Companies, 1959 July-Dec. (Box 7)
  - Tour Companies, 1959 Jan.-June (Box 7)
  - Virginia State Bar Association, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Virginia Travel Council, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Williamsburg Chamber of Commerce, 1959 (Box 7)
  - Amoco, 1957-1958 (Box 7)
  - Special Visits, 1957-1958 (Box 7)
  - Special Events, 1957-1958 (Box 7)
  - Report on Audit, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Advertising, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Atlantic Express Lines of America, Inc., 1963 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Travel Council, 1963 (Box 8)
  - American Association of Museums, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Jamestown Foundation - Minutes, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Williamsburg - Clubs & Organizations, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Concession - Gift Shop, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Equipment - Costumes, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Colonial Williamsburg, Inc., 1963 (Box 8)
  - Educational Material, Request for, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Films, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Exhibits - Gifts to Jamestown Foundation, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Films, Groups Request for, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Exhibits - Request for Loan, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Exhibits - Maintenance & Records, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Films, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Chamber of Commerce, Virginia, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Chamber of Commerce, Williamsburg & Others, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Jamestown Foundation - Policy Governing Guests, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Jamestown Foundation - Library, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Jamestown Foundation - Financial Statements, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Jamestown Foundation - Board of Directors Meetings, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Jamestown Foundation Award, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Education Association, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Jamestown Foundation - Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Jamestown Committee, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Equipment - Uniforms, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Equipment - General, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Meetings, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Grounds & Buildings - James Fort, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Grounds & Buildings - General, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Grounds & Buildings - Office Expansion, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Grounds & Buildings - Flags, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Indians, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Passes, Applications for, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Publicity Releases (Bulk), 1963 (Box 8)
  - Publicity Releases, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Research, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Special Events - Jamestown Day, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Pocahontas, 1962-1963 (Box 8)
  - Ships, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Special Events - 1964 Naval Review, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Visits - School Groups, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Special Events - General, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Training - Refresher Classes, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Visits - Questionnaires, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Visits - Groups, General, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Visitation - Attendance Figues, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Special Events - General Assembly Day, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Visits - Special Groups, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Press Releases, 1958 (Box 8)
  - APVA, 1966-1968 (Box 9)
  - Buildings & Grounds - General, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Capital Outlay, 1966-1968 (Box 9)
  - Chambers of Commerce, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Compliments & Complaints, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Costumes, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Gift Shop, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Films, Request for, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Fort, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Inquiries, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - Jamestown Foundation - Financial Reports, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Jamestown Foundation - Meetings of the Board, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Literature, Requests for, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Mermaid Tavern, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Mobile Travel Guide, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Passes, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Pavilions, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Photographs, Requests for, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Promotions - Outside Jamestown Festival Park, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Publications, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - Publicity - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Publicity - Clippings, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Signs, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Regrets, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Rooms, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Invitation, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Releases, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Speaker, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Acceptances, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Special Events - Jamestown Day, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Special Events - General, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Special Events - Charter Day (William & Mary), 1968 (Box 9)
  - Teachers' Questionnaires, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Dinner, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Speech, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Virginia Travel Committees, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Visitation - Conventions, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Visitation - General, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Visitation - Special Groups, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Visitation - Statistics, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Special Events - First Assembly Day, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Program, 1966-1968 (Box 9)
  - OP Plan, 1968 (Box 9)
  - First Assembly Proceedings, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Proceedings 1619, 1968-1970 (Box 9)
  - Advertising, 1966-1970 (Box 10)
  - Agenda - Current, 1966 (Box 10)
  - Amoco Service Station, 1966 (Box 10)
  - APVA, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Budgets, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Buildings & Grounds, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Capital Outlay, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Chambers of Commerce, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Compliments & Complaints, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Costumes, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Films, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Fort, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Gift Shop, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Indian Museum (Proposed), 1966 (Box 10)
  - Inquiries, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Ships, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Signs, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Jamestown Award, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Jamestown Foundation Financial Reports, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Jamestown Foundation Meetings of the Board, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Literature, Requests for, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Jamestown Foundation Trustees, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Mermaid Tavern, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Museums - Other, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Passes, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Pavilions, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Photos - Requests for, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Pottery, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Promotions - Outside Jamestown Festival Park, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Statutes At Large - Hening, 1967-1969 (Box 10)
  - Essays on Representative Government, 1967-1969 (Box 10)
  - Publications, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Publicity - Clippings, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Publicity - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Research, 1967 (Box 10)
  - Special Events - General, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Lists, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Mailing Lists, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Southern Legislative Conference, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Painting, 1968-1971 (Box 10)
  - Bermuda (350th Anniversary & Parliament), 1970 (Box 10)
  - Indian Fest, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Special Events - Jamestown Day, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Special Events - readings (Proceedings of the Virginia Assembly of 1619 & General Instruct), 1966 (Box 10)
  - Thanksgiving - First, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Virginia Travel Committees, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Visitation - Convention, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Visitation - General, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Visitation - Special Groups, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Trip to England, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Visitation - Statistics, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Jamestown Festival Park - Ships, 1970 (Box 10)
  - Calendar, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Publications, 1956-1968 (Box 11)
  - Advertising, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Agenda, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Amoco Service station, 1971 (Box 11)
  - APVA, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Beverage Inventory, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Budgets, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Capital Outlay, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Chambers of Commerce, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Compliments & Complaints, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Costumes, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
  - Buildings & Grounds, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Films, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
  - Fort, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Gift Shop, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
  - Inquiries, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Jamestown Award, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Jamestown Foundation Financial Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
  - Jamestown Foundation Meetings of the Board, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Jamestown Foundation Meetings of the Board, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Jamestown Foundation Meetings of the Board, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Jamestown Foundation Trustees, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Literature, Request for, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Mermaid Tavern, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Museums (Other), 1971 (Box 11)
  - Passes, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Pavilions, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Photographs - Requests for, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Pottery, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Promotions - Outside Jamestown Festival Park, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Publications, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Publicity - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
  - Publicity - Releases, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Kodak, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Publicity - Clippings, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Ships, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Signs, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Special Events - General, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Special Events - Jamestown Day, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Indian Festival, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
  - Republican Governors, 1971-1972 (Box 11)
  - Republican Governors, 1971-1972 (Box 11)
  - Union Camp, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
  - Teachers' Questionnaires, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Thanksgiving - First, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Tour Boat, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Virginia History Foundation, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Virginia Travel Committees, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Visitation Convention, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Visitation - General, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Visitation - Special Groups, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Visitation - Statistics, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Ships, 1967-1968 (Box 12)
  - First Assembly Day, 1972 July 29 (Box 12)
  - Amoco Service Station, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Budgets, 1972 (Box 12)